Welcome to this week's episode of AI
News You Can Use special edition because
we're on our team retreat in Portugal.
But that doesn't change anything about
the fact that we have a ton of new AI
releases to cover this week and it's a
very practical one if I may say so
myself. We have a brand new app that
checks if your website is ready for the
AI era. GPD's most important feature is
now available to all free users. and so
much more in this week's episode of AI
news you can use the show that takes all
the AI releases of this week filters for
the most important ones and then I get
to present them back to you. Oh, and if
you're worried the entire video is going
to be presented from within the store,
don't be. Let's do this. So, I'm
actually really excited for the main
story this week because this is
something we've seen people request over
and over both in our community and all
across the internet. It's figuring out
if your website is AI ready. In other
words, if LLMs are going to index your
website and serve it up as an answer to
people's prompts. There have been some
approaches now, but I think this release
is the best thing I've seen so far for
this because it's a open-source app from
Firecrawl, which you might already know
as one of the most popular services to
search the web to check if your website
is AI ready. Now, in this tweet, you can
see the CEO of Firecrawl shared this on
Twitter a few days ago. It's actually
not getting a lot of attention, which
surprised me personally. And this app is
fully open source and available on
GitHub. Now the problem here is that you
would need to download this, install it
on your own machine, insert the API key,
and then run the app locally to do this,
which is a high barrier of entry. And as
we are on our weekly retreat here, and
we have the entire team, when we saw
this app, it immediately occurred to us
that hosting this on the web for the
viewers of the show would be a great
idea. So Durk, who's one of the most
active community members who's here with
us, did exactly that for you. want to
briefly join me, Durk? Okay, Derek. So,
just briefly tell us what did you do
here with this open source application?
>> Well, I enhanced it in a way so that you
can use it much more easily and it's
much more into your workflows. You can
not only see what the app tells you what
to improve, but it also gives you a
download for a markdown file that gives
you a complete actionable plan on what
to implement, how to implement it, and
you can also give this to your AI to let
it do that for you.
>> Yes. Exactly. And I think this is really
smart. So if you open up this website
that we hosted on Verscell, you can see
that it first asks for API keys which
I'm just going to put in here. So you
get these by creating OpenAI and
Firewall account and then it immediately
works and I could just go ahead and I
could just type in the URL of the
company website analyze site and as Turk
mentioned the basic app would give you
just this. It shows you hey you're 70%
of the way there and it gives the
details on the different points what you
did well and what's missing. So in this
case we should add a LLM text file, a
robots text file and a site map. But
what Durk did here is he added this
download report button, right? So you
could just press this and you get a
markdown file with all the instructions
for any AI assistant to actually do the
stuff that this app suggests. So as you
can see, it's the whole reports and then
in the end, I believe there's the
instructions here. Yeah. So if you give
this to something like plot code or
cursor and it has access to your
website, it can just do it and you don't
even have to hire a dev to get it done
for you. Matter of fact, after this
recording is done, I'll just run that
and I'll show you a screenshot of the
score of our website.
And also, one more thing, big
disclaimer, we kind of just hacked this
up in a day. So, no guarantees
whatsoever. We just took the onetoone
open source repo and hosted it for you.
But we're not charging for this or
guaranteeing that this works flawlessly.
Yet, I think this is something that
everybody should look into doing because
I can tell you if you look for certain
search terms in chat, some of my YouTube
videos actually rank there because
YouTube did a really good job with
optimizing the videos for LLMs and you
should do the same with your website.
>> Okay, good luck with the next story.
>> One quick follow-up to last week's video
is we talked about the new version of
the Google Translate app and as many of
you correctly pointed out, actually made
a mistake during my demo and I want to
remedy that in this video. So, it's very
subtle, but when you go to this
conversational feature, it's this AI
button here in the middle that allows
you to engage the new AI mode. To me, it
seems that the other mode also uses AI,
but this explicitly reads things out
loud and live translates with AI. So,
everything covered in last week's video
stands. It's just this little sparkle
button that you want to hit to try the
new feature. Very powerful. Been trying
it and it's quite good at live
translation. Make sure to update your
app and check it out. All right. So,
next up, I want to show you one of the
best ways to turn your ideas into real
apps. both mobile and desktop. That's
the key here. Using AI, and that is with
anything, the sponsor of today's video,
anything lets you create powerful mobile
apps and websites. And all you need is
one skill, communication. No coding
required at all. If you can imagine it
and put your ideas into words, anything
can transform those words into a real
app. And if you've ever used Chat GPT at
all, the platform will feel very
familiar. As you can see, there's not a
wall of code overwhelming you. Just a
simple chat interface. And the part that
I really want to highlight here is how
good they're at creating mobile apps.
So, if you're following this channel,
you might be familiar with many of the
workflows we covered, but usually the
focus is web apps and mobile apps are an
afterthought. That's not the case here.
You can build native mobile apps and web
apps with the same back end. You can see
instant previews of them on your phone
and they have a one-click submit to the
application store. Everything is
included here. front end, backend,
database, AI integrations, and you can
build it all with natural language, just
like you would be messaging a developer.
So, if you have an idea for a mobile
app, anything lets you go from idea to
live app in hours using just prompts. No
coding or extra tools required at all.
So, if that sounds good to you, go check
out anything today. Use the code AI
advantage to get $10 off your first
month. And now, let's get back to the
next piece of AI news that you can use.
Okay, so for the next story, I want you
to pay attention, especially if you're
not a paid user in chatb. I personally
think projects are the most powerful
feature they have ever shipped. It's the
best interface to manage context which
as you might know is the key to getting
good results from chatbt. Up until now
only the paid accounts had them. Now in
your free account you yourself can use
projects and we already have a video in
the pipeline teaching you how to set
them up for yourself how to compare to
memories custom instructions GPTs.
Subscribe if you want that. It's going
to be coming out soon. We just have to
rework it a little bit because in my
recording of that video, this was a
premium paid feature and a very powerful
one and now all the free users have it.
So if you're on a free account, go check
out projects instead of one for personal
chats, one for work chats. And if you
want more guidance, have a look at the
video that's coming soon. All right,
next up we have Genspark Clip Genius, a
new feature by the Agentic app that kind
of tries to do it all. At least that's
what I would conclude from the recent
releases. And this time they're trying
to do video editing. We tested this with
a few examples and compared it to some
of our manual editing efforts recently.
Concretely, what we did is give it a
lecture from our community on chatb
connectors that I held and we manual
edited a short/real from this which
turned out great. To compare, we also
gave Jensen Spark the same source video
and gave it the following prompt.
Understand the video, select one topic
or quote and create a vertical video
that is less than 60 seconds. And the
result, I wouldn't even show the whole
thing here cuz honestly, it's not worth
your time. First of all, it's not
vertical at all. It can re-edit 16 to9
to 16 to9 which would be fine by itself
but it just picked a segment of the
video that is first of all not even a
really good segment. I suppose if you're
just looking at the transcript it's
okayish which is what this tool does and
secondly it didn't even edit much. It
kind of just took out one part if I saw
this correctly. And in some other
testing we did it didn't even take out
one part. It kind of just clips
something and gives it to you and says
hey this is the edit that I came up
with. So, while this might be a
interesting category right now, you can
think of it as a automatic way to
transcribe something and then pick a few
parts of the transcript that might work
as a video, but reviewing that is
probably more work than just clipping
those things yourself right now.
>> We are not going to lose our job.
>> So, my editing team, which is actually
here helping with the recording right
now, guys, this is terrible. No need to
be afraid.
>> All right, let's move on to the next
one. Okay, next up, we have some updates
to Notebook LM. I always like featuring
these because this is one of the most
powerful apps in the entire AI space. If
you missed it, we uploaded a four-minute
tutorial that covers the entire app. How
to use it, what to use it for. So, make
sure to check that out if you're new to
it. If you're already familiar, then you
will want to see this new feature, which
are new formats for the audio overviews,
aka podcasts as many people call them.
Instead of just creating the typical
deep dive that you get with these
podcasts, you can also switch it to
brief, to a critique, or to a debate
format. One interesting thing to note
here is that all of these come with
separate voices too.
>> This is the brief on
>> welcome to the critique. Welcome to the
debate.
>> So if I just open one of my recent
notebooks, go to audio overviews, you
can see these new presets right here. If
I flip the preset to brief and I say,
tell me about hooks, then this audio
overview should reflect that and not be
a 5 10 15 minute file as it so often is
with the default preset. So here's the
little audio overview/podcast that we
got from the concise preset. This is the
brief on mastering clawed code, advanced
workflows and responsible vibe coding.
>> Okay, so it sounds good. Obviously,
we'll have the same problems the
original audio overviews had, which is
sometimes it just misses the mark on the
question you give it, but it's
definitely more concise. This is a
2-minute video, and from multiple long
sources like this without the preset,
you could expect something multiple
times as long. Okay, for the next one,
we have a category that I particularly
like cuz it's video production related.
It's 11 laps sound effects now in
version 2. So, the announcement here is
relatively minor. The duration of the
clips you can generate went from 22
seconds to 30 seconds. The bit rate is
higher and you can create sound effects
that loop seamlessly, which can be nice.
Now, they presented it as a brand new
release. So, we went ahead and tested it
and compared it to some of the sound
effects that we generated with version
one. And the overall result, eh, it's
similar or not identical quality level
to the first version. And classic
professionally recorded sound effects
still sound better. But nevertheless,
let me give it a super quick test. So,
let's just follow what they recommend.
Go to animals. And how about a seal in
distress? I believe the children are our
future.
>> Okay, we got four.
>> What is that?
>> No.
[Laughter]
That's like a person impersonating a
seal in distress, not a actual seal. No.
So, I would say for the purpose of this
video, this worked exceptionally well.
If I needed that sound effect, no, just
no. And that's even the category they
recommended. So, let's just move on.
Okay, one more time, maybe.
[Music]
Oh my god. Okay, thank you, Eleven Labs.
Okay, next up, let's do this week's
quick hits. the stories that are worth
talking about, but maybe we don't need
to spend multiple minutes on them.
Starting out with updates to Mistral's
Lat. They're really expanding their
platform with some of the
state-of-the-art features like MCP
connectors. They added memories to the
entire application and I would argue
that these two are actually the most
important features you can have in a
platform like this and they even allow
you to do custom MCPS. Now, then also we
have Chach adding parental controls into
Chachib. So, this isn't rolling out yet,
but some new lawsuits in the US where
parents blame OpenAI for manipulating
their children into certain behaviors
are happening right now, and this seems
like a direct reaction to that. And I
guess it makes sense. I personally more
interested in this trend here that
they're going to be adding more guard
rails and manual controls on how all of
this can be used, starting with parental
controls. So, we'll keep you posted once
that is actually implemented. Next up,
we have a new model coming out of Grock
focused on coding, uh, fast coding, that
is. It's literally called rock code fast
one. And I think this graph says it all.
It's very cheap with high tokens per
second, but obviously you're not getting
state-of-the-art quality here.
Interesting for some niche developer use
cases. And then we have some new models
from Microsoft called MAI as in
Microsoft AI, I believe. Preview and
MAI1 voice. Honestly, these are nothing
special and they're just slowly
releasing them to certain people. They
even include wording in their blog post
that, hey, don't judge these too
harshly. We're developing these. But I
do want to note that these are
integrated in copilot which for many
enterprises is the only choice. And as
we kind of reviewed copilot for this
story, we noticed a lot of interesting
updates including one that I wanted to
highlight which is a daily news roundup
automatically generated for you within
Copilot. This is something we don't see
in other LLM platforms. And I like to
highlight features like that because
eventually you'll see them trickle down
into chat GPT if they catch on. And I
personally found that even more
interesting than the new models here.
But yeah, now you know about both. In
the AI video world, Hicksfield also
released two new features. None of them
revolutionary, but both interesting. One
of them is draw toedit uh interactive
canvas where you can use the new
nanobana model and you can edit and
animate allin-one visual interface. It
also allows you to really easily use
multiple models. So if you do that,
check this out as an option. And
secondly, they released Speak 2.0, which
is something similar to Hen both in the
functionality and the quality. I think
Hen calls this avatar IV where you just
upload an image and it turns it into a
video. You can do the same with
Hicksfield now. And you just select one
of their voices, give it a script or
generate one, and then you get an
okayish AI video. And that's really
everything for this week. I hope you
found something that was useful or
inspirative to you. Recently, we
uploaded a lot of high-quality
educational videos. So, if you want a
80-minute course on cloud code or a
4-minute intro to Notebook LM, you can
check them out right here. And if you're
enjoying this content, don't forget to
subscribe. And with that being said, my
name is Igor and I will see you next